A Finding Aid to the Walter Horn Papers, 1908-1992, bulk 1943-1950, in the Archives of American Art AAA.hornwalt
Archives of American Art
Walter Horn papers
bulk 1943-1950
1908-1992
AAA.hornwalt
Archives of American Art
2.7 Linear feet
The papers of art historian and World War II Monuments Man Walter W. Horn measure 2.7 linear feet and date from 1908 to 1992, with the bulk of material dating from 1943 to 1950. Walter Horn taught art history at the University of California, Berkeley from 1938 to his retirement in 1974. During World War II, Horn served as Head of the U. S. Army Intelligence Unit of the Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives Section (MFAA.) The papers contain biographical materials; professional correspondence; records documenting his service in the MFAA; administrative files relating to his work at the University of California, Berkeley; and scattered photographs.
Horn, Walter William, 1908-1995
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Walter Horn donated his papers to the Archives of American Art in 1989. Additional papers were donated by his wife Dr. Alberta Parker Horn in 1998 and 2002.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of art historian and World War II Monuments Man Walter W. Horn measure 2.7 linear feet and date from 1908 to 1992, with the bulk of material dating from 1943 to 1950. Walter Horn taught art history at the University of California, Berkeley from 1938 to his retirement in 1974. During World War II, Horn served as Head of the U. S. Army Intelligence Unit of the Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives Section (MFAA.) The papers contain biographical materials; professional correspondence; records documenting his service in the MFAA; administrative files relating to his work at the University of California, Berkeley; and scattered photographs.
Biographical materials include certificates, transcripts, registration books, and diplomas, immigration papers and supporting documentation, birth certificate, passports, and Horn's application for U.S. citizenship. Also found here are papers relating to Horn's academic work, such as bibliographies, curriculum vitae and a few other miscellaneous materials.
The bulk of the papers consist of professional correspondence between Horn and his colleagues. Many of the letters relate to Horn's scholarly publications and projects, especially his seminal work The Plan of St. Gall: A Plan of the Architecture and Economy of, and Life in a Paradigmatic Carolingian Monastery (1979). Prominent correspondents include Meyer Schapiro, Wilhelm Koehler, Fred Charles, Christopher Eggenbacher, Johannes Duft, Hunter Dupree, Peter Harbison, H.R. Sennhauser, and John T. Smith.
Papers and records documenting Horn's World War II service in the the U. S. Army Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section have been arranged in one series. There are scattered letters, including ones from Erwin Panofsky, Charles J. Kunzelman, and Helmuth and Edeltraut von Hummel. There are also letters of inquiry about the recovery of the crown jewels of The Holy Roman Empire. Also found in this series are official Army documents, including a directory and inventory of recovered gold coins; receipts for transporting recovered artwork; art looting investigation, interrogation, and arrest reports; and reports on Horn's investigation and recovery of the crown jewels and the gold coin investigation. There is scattered printed material and photographs of the recovered gold coins and of Helmuth and Edeltraut von Hummel.
Horn's papers also contain a few administrative files from his tenure at the University of California, Berkeley, and one folder of color photographs of Horn's papers being prepared for shipment to the Archives of American Art.
Biographical/Historical note
Walter William Horn (1908-1995) was a professor of art history at the University of California, Berkeley. During World War II, he served in the Army Intelligence Unit of the Monument, Fine Arts and Archives Section (MFAA.)
Walter Horn was born in Waldangelloch, Germany and graduated from the Gymnasium in Heidelberg in 1926. He studied at the Universities of Heidelberg, Berlin and Hamburg. In 1934 he received his Ph.D. in art history from the University of Hamburg, studying under Erwin Panofsky. His dissertation on the facade of the Church of St. Gilles was published in 1937. Horn fled Nazism in Germany and immigrated to the United States.
In 1938 Horn accepted a position at the University of California at Berkeley as a lecturer in art history, becoming the first state sponsored teacher of art history within California. He quickly became a professor and co-founded the university's Department of Art History.
Horn married twice. His first wife was Ann Binkley Rand. His second marriage was to Alberta West Parker, a physician. They had three children, Michael Peters, Peter Matthew, and Rebecca Ann.
In 1943, Horn became a naturalized American citizen and was soon inducted into the U.S. Army. He was assigned to the Detailed Interrogation Center, and by 1945 was serving as a lieutenant in the Third Army Intelligence Center. His German language skills were put to use interrogating prisoners of war and personnel of the Gestapo and S.S. Horn later continued his interrogation work in the Supreme Headquarters Allied Expeditionary Force (SHAEF). After the war, Horn was assigned to the Army Intelligence Unit of the Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section (MFAA) and became one of the Monuments Men responsible for tracking and recovering art works and other cultural heritage objects that had been systematically looted and hidden by the Nazis.
Horn led the team of Monuments Men who recovered the stolen Crown Jewels or Imperial Regalia of the Holy Roman Empire. The Crown Jewels, including a crown and sceptre, were discovered walled up in a passage in Nuremburg. Horn also recovered a collection of gold coins valued at $2,000,000 in 1946. He tracked the coins primarily through interrogations of Edeltraut von Hummel. Edeltraut's husband Helmuth von Hummel served as the chief secretary to Martin Bormann, leader of the Nazi Party Chancellery.
After the war, Horn resumed teaching at the University of California, Berkeley, where he served as Chairman of the Department of Art History until his retirement in 1974. He also helped establish the University Art Museum. In 1949, the school implemented a requirement that all employees must sign a loyalty oath to affirm their allegiance to the state constitution and disavow any intent to overthrow the government. There was substantial outcry among the university faculty and several professors who refused to sign were fired. Horn signed the loyalty oath under protest in 1950. He wrote a letter to the press explaining his decision and expressing his concerns.
In 1979, a decades long collaboration with distinguished architect Ernest Born resulted in The Plan of St. Gall, a three volume work on medieval architecture. The book was praised as a monumental undertaking by the scholarly community upon its publication.
Walter Horn died of pneumonia in 1995.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 5 series.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1908-1989 (0.3 linear feet; Box 1, 4)
Series 2: Correspondence, circa 1937, 1949-1992 (1.2 linear feet; Box 1-2, 4, OV 5)
Series 3: U.S. Army Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section Files, circa 1938-1989 (0.6 linear feet; Box 2-4, OV 5-6)
Series 4: University of California, Berkeley Administrative Files, 1938-1976 (0.1 linear feet; Box 3)
Series 5: Photographs, 1989 (1 folder; Box 3)
Allied Forces. Supreme Headquarters. Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Section.; Charles, Fred; Duft, Johannes; Dupree, Hunter; Eggenbacher, Christopher; Harbison, Peter; Koehler, Wilhelm Reinhold Walter, 1884-1959; Kunzelman, Charles J.; Panofsky, Erwin, 1892-1968; Sennhauser, H. R.; Shapiro, Meyer; Smith, John T.; University of California, Berkeley -- Faculty; von Hummel, Edeltraut; von Hummel, Helmuth; Art historians--California--Berkeley; Art thefts--Germany--History--20th century; Crown jewels--Holy Roman Empire; Photographs; World War, 1939-1945--Art and the war; World War, 1939-1945--Confiscations and contributions--Germany; World War, 1939-1945--Destruction and pillage--Europe
- Biographical Materials, 1908-1989; Series 1; 0.3 Linear feet Box 1, 4
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical materials include Horn's birth certificate, registration books, Ph.D. diploma, immigration and naturalization documents, passports and driver's license. Other papers includes bibliographies, fellowship appointments, curriculum vitaes, reviews for publications, and a speech reflecting on his experiences in America.
  - Birth Certificate and Related Forms, 1908-1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Gymnasium Certificate, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University of Heidelberg and the University of Berlin Undergraduate Registration Books, 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - University of Hamburg Registration Book, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - German Passport and Driver's License, 1932-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Oral Ph.D. Examination and Evaluation, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ph.D. Diploma and Dissertation Program, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, Folder 1.
  - Official German Document on Background Check, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Immigration Forms and Citizenship Application, 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Naturalization Certificate, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Passport, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bibliographies, 1962-1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, Folder 2.
  - Articles and Reviews of Publications, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Untitled Speech About Experiences in America, circa 1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Short Biography for The Plan of St. Gall Deluxe Edition, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fellowship Awards, 1981-1988; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Contemporary Authors Biography, circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Biographies, circa 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - J. Paul Getty Trust Bulletin, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, Folder 3.
  - Oversized Diploma and Copies, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 7.
  - Oversized Photocopy of Bibliography Page, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 13.
  - Oversized J. Paul Getty Trust Bulletin, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 20.
- Correspondence, 1949-1992; circa 1937; Series 2; 1.2 Linear feet Box 1-2, 4, OV 5
  This series is comprised of professional correspondence, mostly from his colleagues at the University of California, Berkeley. Correspondents include Christoph Eggenberger, Fred Charles, Johannes Duft, Hunter Dupree, Peter Harbison, H.R. Sennhauser and John T. Smith, Meyer Schapiro, and Wilhelm Koehle.
  Arrangement note
  Files are arranged in alphabetical order according to name of correspondent or subject.
  - Allen, Roger, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Andersen, Jock, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Arens, Fritz, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Barton, Brigid S., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Berger, Rainer, 1987; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bessler, Hans, 1952-1959 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, Folder 4.
  - Blaine, Bradford, 1967; 1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brown, T. J., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Buddensieg, Tilmann, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Charles, Fred, 1967-1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, Folder 5.
  - Charles, Martin, 1980; 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Colvin, Howard, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Conant, Kenneth, 1958; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Courtenay, Lynn T., 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Cramp, Rosemary, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Dendooven, Lucien, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dresbeck, LeRoy, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Duft, Johannes, 1951-1968, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Dupree, Hunter, 1968-1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Dupree, Hunter, 1978-1991 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Deuchler, Florens, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Includes two slides: one an old city plan of Wolfenbuttel, Germany and the other a drawing from Dusseldorf evangelary.
  - Eggenberger, Christoph, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Oversized material housed in OV 5, Folder 1.
  - Fehr, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Fink, P. Wilhelm, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Fitchens, John, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Forsyth, George H., 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Foster, Philip, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Ganshof, F. L., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Giertz, Veronika, circa 1974 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Golden, Grace, 1969; 1975 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Gordon, Arthur E., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Gross, Walter H., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Grubald, circa 1937 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Gruber, Karl, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Hamm, Franz Josef, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Harbison, Peter, 1970-1991 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, Folder 6.
  - Hart, William, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Herity, Michael, 1993; 1984 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Heydenreich, L. H., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Hill, Ordelle G., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Hodges, Richard, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Huber, Florian, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Hugot, Leo, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Jacobsen, Werner, 1978; 1983 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Janson, Peter, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Jones, Charles W., 1967-1990 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Jung, Hermann, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Kantorowicz, Ernst, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Kelly, Dorothy, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Kilburn, J. R., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Kincaid, R. P., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Kirk, Malcolm, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Kitzinger, Ernst, 1967; 1986 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Kleinbauer, Eugene, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Koehler, Wilhelm, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Kostof, Spiro, 1982; 1978 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Krautheimer, Richard, 1962-1977 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Kubach, Erich, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Land, W. G., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Landauer, Carl, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Lillich, Meredith, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Ludi, Heinz, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Ludwig, Peter, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Lyman, Thomas W., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Malone, Carolyn, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Marrow, James, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - McCrum, Sean, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - McKitterick, Rosamond, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Melia, Dan, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Meyvaert, Paul, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Middeldorf, Ulrich, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Miller, Naomi, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Mitchell, Frank, 1977-1990 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Morrisey, Richard J., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Munby, Julian, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Noll, Gunter, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Nordenfalk, Carl, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Ochsenbein, Peter, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - O'Shaughnessy, Aighleann, 1983; 1981 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Platt, Colin, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Price, Lorna, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Prinz, Friedrich, 1974-1986 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Probst, P. Benedict Hubert, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Quinlan, Honor, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Rahtz, Philip, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Raleigh, John Henry, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Randell, Cork and Dick, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Ridgway, P. W., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Rourke, Grellan, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Schapiro, Meyer, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Schepers, Josef, 1967; 1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Schultz, Juergen, 1967-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Selz, Peter, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sennhauser, H. R., 1986; 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    Oversized material housed in OV 5, Folder 2.
  - Smith, John T., 1967-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Includes 2 black & white photographs of a demolished barn at Petersborough.
  - Spencer, Harold, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stalley, Roger, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Stechow, Wolfgang, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Stern, Richard, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Striker, Cecil L., 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Tennant, Elaine C., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Toker, Franklin, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Twohig, Elizabeth, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Verdon, Gregory, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Vincent, A. W. B., 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Wenger, Luke, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Wieck, Roger S., 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Weller, John, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Wendland, Ulrike, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - White, Lynn, 1967-1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Wilsdorf, Christian, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified Correspondents, 1963-1987 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Fan Mail, 1985-1989; 1973 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Frocester Court, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Ireland Trip to Skellig Rock, 1979-circa 1983 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "Middle Littleton" Article Congratulations, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Renaissance of the Twelfth Century Conference, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Reprints of "On the Origins of the Medieval Bay System", 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Santa Maria de Oliva, 1977-1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Oversized material housed in Box 4, Folder 7.
  - St. Gall, 1950-1958 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Oversized Newspaper Clipping, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 26.
  - Oversized Blueprints of Frocester Court, 1967-1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 30.
  - Oversized Image of Artwork, 1970-1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 56.
  - Oversized Newspaper Clipping, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Oversized material from Box 2, Folder 31.
  - Oversized Timeline for Exhibition Planning, circa 1981 (Box OV 5, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 42.
  - Oversized Floor Plan of St. Gall, 1970-1977 (Box OV 5, Folder 2)
    Oversized material from Box 2, Folder 5.
- U. S. Army Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section Files, circa 1938-1989; Series 3; 0.6 Linear feet Box 2-4, OV 5-6
  Documentation of Walter Horn's World War II service during and immediately following World War II in U.S. Army Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section is found in this file. There are official Army reports and publications, interrogation and looting reports and inventories, scattered correspondence, printed materials, and a few photographs.
  This series is arranged as 6 subseries:
  3.1: Correspondence, 1943-1947, 1972-1989
  3.2: Writings, circa 1945-1983
  3.3: Army Documents, 1943-1952, 1983
  3.4: Art Looting and Interrogation Reports, 1945-1946
  3.5: Printed Materials, circa 1938-1949, 1975-1983
  3.6: Photographs, 1945-1946
  - Correspondence, 1943-1947; 1972-1989; 3.1
    Correspondence in this series relates specifically to Horn's work in the MFAA Section. There is a letter from Erwin Panofsky regarding Horn's decision to volunteer for the U.S. Army and several letters from Charles J. Kunzelman, a retired army colonel, who was interested in Horn's MFAA work and was trying to get Horn an award for his recovery efforts, particularly for the Crown Jewels of the Holy Roman Empire and a large cache of gold coins. There is one letter from the wife of Helmuth von Hummel. Helmuth was the secretary of SS official Martin Bormann, and Horn discovered the location of the missing gold coins by questioning his wife Edeltraut.
    - Board of Correction of Military Records, circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Buhler, Albert, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Oversized material housed in OV 5, Folder 3.
    - Fries, Liselotte, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Kunzelman, Charles J., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Kunzelman, Charles J., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Odegaard, Charles E., circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Panofsky, Erwin, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Potok, Isidor, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Scheidler, Iris, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - von Hummel, Helmuth and Edeltraut, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      Originals of the photographs of Edeltraut and Helmuth von Hummel are filed in series 3.5.
    - Watson, Peter, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Crown Jewels: Later Inquiries, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Oversized Newsclippings, 1972-1975 (Box OV 5, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 2, Folder 34.
  - Writings, circa 1945-1983; 3.2
    Found here are a few of Horn's lectures about his service as one of the Monuments Men and one folder of miscellaneous notes. There is also one folder with a typescript draft of a lecture about the restitution activities of the Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives section whose authorship is unknown.
    - Miscellaneous Monuments Men Notes, circa 1945-1974 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "War's Toll on Italian Art", circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "Nazi Art", circa 1950-circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Restitution Activities, circa 1950-circa 1960 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      This is a typescript draft of a lecture (first two pages missing) about Monuments Men recovery efforts and collecting points. Horn probably wrote this but the authorship is uncertain since the events described do not reflect Horn's activities or responsibilities as a Monuments Man.
    - "Wiesbaden Manifesto", 1950s (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - "The Finding of the Crown Jewels", 1965 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - "Recovery of Missing Crown Jewels", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Army Documents, 1943-1952; 1983; 3.3
    Found here are official U.S. Army documents, publications, and reports. There is also an inventory of recovered gold coins and receipts for transporting recovered artwork.
    - Army Directives, 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Appointments and Promotions, 1943-1952 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Certificates, 1944-1950 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Weisbaden Manifesto Protesting Removal of German-Owned Art to America, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Receipts and Documents about Transporting Art, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Inventory of Missing Gold Coins for the Linz Museum, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Organized Reserve Corps Documents, 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Army Directory, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Forms and Questionnaires, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      Oversized material housed in OV 5, Folder 4.
    - Transcripts of interviews with Konrad Fries and Heinz Schmeissner, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Oversized Reserve Officer Questionnaire, 1951 (Box OV 5, Folder 4)
      Oversized material from Box 2, Folder 61.
  - Art Looting Investigation and Interrogation Reports, 1945-1946; 3.4
    Found here are the official army reports on investigations, interrogations and arrests. A few of the reports were written by Horn and include interrogations he conducted with prisoners of war. Nearly all of the reports relate to stolen artwork and cultural icons.
    - "Collection of German Letters and Memoranda Pertaining to Confiscation of European Art Treasures", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      This folder contains a Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives section report with translations of letters and memoranda between Hitler and Nazi officials referring to looting artwork.
    - Dreykorn Report, "History of the Imperial Crown Jewels", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Horn's Report on the Crown Jewels Investigation and Recovery, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Illegal Transfer of Art Works from the Collection of Willi Sachs, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - War Room Publication: AMT III RSHA and the S.D. in Germany, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Arrest Reports, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Interrogation Reports by Lieutenant Hill, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Interrogation Reports 7-9, 16, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Interrogation Report about Wilfrid Kochert, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Interrogation Reports, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 72)